

# Rubén D. Pire

# **Full-Stack Web Developer**

rubenpire7@gmail.com || GitHub || LinkedIn || Portfolio

## **Summary**

I am a full-stack web developer and React enthusiast passionate about clean and easy-to-follow code, with experience in pair programming and remote work. Fluent in several languages, frameworks, and technologies, and a team player with an optimistic personality that can boost the morale of any team.

#### Skills

Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Redux, SASS

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Work, Pair-Programming, Teamwork

# **Experience**

### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

July 2021 - Present

OLC Re-opening Website — A re-opening website for Obelisk Language Center, a Venezuelan language school.

• Built with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

<u>Math Magicians</u> — A calculator application built implementing the React framework with SPA dynamics.

Built with: JavaScript, React

<u>Covid Metrics</u> — An API-based website that possesses SPA dynamics. It displays statistics and information related to the COVID-19 pandemic for regions in the United Kingdom.

• Built with: JavaScript, React, Redux

MICROVERSE Remote

#### Mentor (Volunteer)

October 2021 - Present

Mentored 20+ junior developers, providing technical support, code reviews, and professional ethics.

- Helped boost students' motivation levels and longevity in the program by providing advice and guidance through the curriculum lessons and activities, such as possible approaches and techniques to different challenges or issues.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to enhance code quality and overall performance. By encouraging the use of best practices.

## **Education**

## **MICROVERSE**

July 2021 - February 2022

# Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Accumulated 1300+ hours developing projects both independently and collaboratively, while simultaneously mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development.
- Honed communication skills by pair-programming, using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and following Scrum methodology, with a remote team of international developers.
- Won the "Collaborator of the Month" award, for my excellent performance while working on group projects.

## **UNEXPO**

November 2011 - December 2018

# **Engineering, Electricity**

- Completed coursework about programming logic and algorithms.
- Completed coursework about PLC programming.
- Worked as a university trainer for the Electrical Power Systems I subject, providing complimentary classes, assistance, and project reviews for senior-year undergraduates.